Guide to the Office of the President records ARCH148
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
Office of the President records
Circa 1980 - 2011
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
University of Hartford. Office of the President
ARCH148
55 Linear Feet
Conditions Governing Access
Some files have been restricted due to their confidential content. A review of the files and restrictions in currently in progress.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of memos, correspondence, and working files created by the Office of the President of the University of Hartford primarily during the administrations of Humphrey Tonkin and Walter Harrison. The collection also contains a smaller amount of material generated during the tenure of Stephen Trachtenberg.
The files consist of various topics regarding the University of Hartford and its schools including capital campaigns, strategic planning, projects, initiatives, and events. University Presidents have also been prominent members of non-University organizations. Files regarding their activities in these organizations are included in the collection.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by accession.
Educational fund raising; Universities and colleges -- United States -- Planning; University of Hartford. Office of the President; University of Hartford
- Acc. I Unknown, 32.08 Linear Feet (78 containers)
  - American Center for the Advancement of the Blind (Box 1)
  - American Council on Education (ACE) (Box 1)
  - American Council on Learned Societies (ACLS) (Box 1)
  - American Originals (Box 1)
  - Athletics - Admissions (Box 1, Box 2)
  - Athletics - America East Compliance Review (Box 2)
  - Athletics - America East Conference, 2007-2008 (Box 2, Box 3)
  - Athletics - Brazeu (Box 3)
  - Athletics - General Correspondence (Box 3)
  - Athletics - Home Field Advantage (Box 3)
  - Athletics - NCAA, 1991-1998 (Box 3, Box 4)
  - Athletics - NCAA, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Athletics - Board of Directors, 2003 (Box 4)
  - Athletics - NCAA Certification (Box 4, Box 5)
  - Athletics - Pat Meiser (Box 5)
  - Athletics - NCAA, 2002-2003 (Box 5)
  - All University Curriculum (AUC) (Box 6)
  - ALL University Curriculum (AUC) - Donald Davis (Box 6)
  - ARAMARK (Box 6)
  - ARAMARK - 1990 renovation of University Commons (Box 6)
  - ASK House (Box 6, Box 7)
  - Nutmeg Big Brothers Big Sisters (Box 7)
  - Boys and Girls Club of Hartford (Box 7)
  - Boy Scouts of America (Box 7)
  - Bursar (Box 7)
  - Campaign of Commitment (Box 7, Box 8)
  - Campaign of Commitment - Steering Committee (Box 8)
  - Bond Financing II, 1987 (Box 8)
  - Bond Refinancing, 1993 (Box 8, Box 9)
  - Bond Financing I, 1988 (Box 9)
  - Blue Ribbon Commission (Box 9, Box 10)
  - Campaign of Commitment, 2000-2004, undated (Box 10)
  - Capital Campaign, 1983-1997 (Box 11)
  - Capitol Region Education Council (CREC), 1999-2005 (Box 11)
  - College Board, 2002-2005 (Box 11)
  - Commencement, 1988-2008 (Box 12, Box 13)
  - Commission of Inquiry, 1991 (Box 14)
  - Commission of Inquiry - Documentation and Notification, 1991 (Box 14)
  - Commission of Inquiry - Media Record, 1991 (Box 14)
  - Commission of Inquiry - Alcohol, 1991 (Box 14, Box 15)
  - Commission of Inquiry - Report Updates, 1991 (Box 15)
  - Commission of Inquiry - Incident reports, 1991 (Box 15)
  - Connecticut Conference of Independent Colleges (CCIC), 1999-2004, undated (Box 15, Box 16, Box 17)
  - Connecticut Health and Educational Facilities Authority (CHEFA), 1991-2005 (Box 17)
  - Connecticut Department of Higher Education, 1991-1993; 2002-2005 (Box 17, Box 18)
  - Connecticut Student Loan Foundation (CSLF), 2007-2009 (Box 18, Box 19)
  - Council for Higher Education Accreditation (CHEA), 2002 (Box 19)
  - Deeds Symposium, 1982-1999 (Box 19, Box 20)
  - Discovery Center, 2003-2006 (Box 21)
  - ENHP Physical Therapy Accreditation, 1994-2005 (Box 21)
  - Emeriti Association, 1999-2005 (Box 21)
  - Emerson Quartet, 1993 (Box 21)
  - Financial Aid, 2003-2005 (Box 21, Box 22)
  - Financial Aid - Student Problems, 2001-2005 (Box 22)
  - Follett - Bookstore, 1996-2005 (Box 22)
  - Girl Scouts - Correspondence, 2008-2009 (Box 22, Box 23)
  - Girl Scouts - Reports, 2004-2008 (Box 23)
  - Governor, Circa 2000 - 2006 (Box 23)
  - Gray Center Architectural Proposal - Conference Center (Box 23)
  - Gray Center Architectural Proposal - General Overview (Box 23)
  - Gray Center Architectural Proposal Photograph (Box 23)
  - Gray Center Correspondence, 1987-2004 (Box 23, Box 24)
  - Gray Center - 1877 Club (Box 24)
  - Gray Center - Financing (Box 24)
  - Gray Center - Media (Box 24)
  - Gray Center - Media Coverage (Box 24)
  - Gray Center Photograph (Box 24)
  - Gray Center - Speeches (Box 24)
  - Greater Hartford Homes - Feasibility Studies, 1990 (Box 24, Box 25)
  - Greater Hartford Homes - MPC Associates, 1989 (Box 25)
  - Greater Hartford Homes - Opposition (Box 25)
  - Greenberg Center, 1987-1996 (Box 25)
  - Greenberg Center - General Correspondence, 1998-2002 (Box 25)
  - Greenberg Center - Greater Hartford Jewish Federation, 1987, undated (Box 26)
  - Greenberg Center - Henry Luce Foundation, 1995-2000 (Box 26)
  - Greenberg Center - Articles (Box 26)
  - Greenberg Center - Press Releases (Box 26)
  - Greenberg Center - Morris and Emma Cohen Fund, 1986-1992 (Box 26)
  - Greenberg Center - Museum of Jewish Civilization (Box 26)
  - Greenberg Center - Opening, 1987 (Box 26)
  - Greenberg Center - Programs (Box 26)
  - Greenberg Center - Trachtenberg Correspondence (Box 26)
  - Hartford Art School Inc. Trustees, 1996-2004 (Box 26, Box 27, Box 28)
  - Hartford Courant (Box 28)
  - Hartford Consortium of Higher Education - Board of Governors, 1973-2008; Bulk 2004-2008; Bulk 1991-1997 (Box 28)
  - Hartford Consortium for Higher Education - Draft of Goals for 2004-2005, 2003 (Box 29)
  - Hartford Stage - Audit Results, 2007 (Box 29)
  - Hartford Stage - Board of Directors, 2008-2009 (Box 29)
  - Hartford Stage - Capital Campaign, 2005-2007 (Box 29, Box 30)
  - Hartford Stage - Executive Committee, 2005-2006 (Box 30)
  - Hartford Stage - Finance Committee, 2004-2008 (Box 30, Box 31)
  - Hartford Stage - Governance, 2003-2007 (Box 31)
  - Hartford Symphony, 2005-2007 (Box 31)
  - Hepburn Center, Circa 1994 - circa 1997 (Box 32)
  - Hepburn Center - Cinema Studies, 1995-1996, 2000 (Box 32)
  - Hepburn Center - Films and Film Festival (Box 32)
  - Hepburn - Trachtenberg Invitation for Honorary Degree, 1983 (Box 32)
  - Honorary Degrees, 1987-2003 (Box 32, Box 33, Box 34)
  - Inauguration - Expenses and Income, 1999 (Box 34)
  - Inauguration - Mailings (Box 34)
  - Inauguration - Correspondence (Box 34)
  - Inauguration - Inauguration Committee (Box 34)
  - Inauguration - Ritual and Address (Box 34)
  - Inauguration - Events (Box 34)
  - Inauguration - Printed Materials - Richard Levin (Box 34)
  - Inauguration - Printed Materials - Humphrey Tonkin (Box 34, Box 76)
  - Inauguration - Printed Materials - Nora Kizer Bell (Box 34)
  - Inauguration - Printed Materials - Lee Bollinger (Box 34)
  - Inauguration - Printed Materials - Walter Harrison (Box 34, Box 77)
  - Inauguration - Walter Harrison - Congratulations Letters (Box 34, Box 35)
  - Inauguration - Walter Harrison - Inaugural Year (Box 77, Box 78)
  - Inauguration - Printed Materials - Walter Roettger (Box 35)
  - Inauguration - Printed Materials - Patti McGill Peterson (Box 35)
  - Inauguration - Printed Materials - William Chase (Box 35)
  - Inauguration - Printed Materials - Sherry H. Penney (Box 35)
  - Inauguration - Printed Materials - Glenda Price (Box 35)
  - Inauguration - Printed Materials - Tom Gerety (Box 35)
  - Inauguration - Printed Materials - Trachtenberg (GWU) (Box 35)
  - Inauguration - Printed Materials - Benno C. Schmidt, Jr. (Box 35)
  - Inauguration - Presidential Inaugurations (Box 35)
  - Inauguration - Humphrey Tonkin - Dinner Layout (Box 35)
  - Inauguration - Humphrey Tonkin - Ceremonial Organization (Box 35)
  - Inauguration - Humphrey Tonkin - University Media (Box 35)
  - Inauguration - Humphrey Tonkin - Inauguration Ritual, 1989 (Box 36)
  - Inauguration - Humphrey Tonkin - Speeches, 1989 (Box 36)
  - Inauguration - Humphrey Tonkin - Observer, 1989 (Box 36)
  - Inauguration - Humphrey Tonkin - Dinner - Centerpiece - ACE, 1989 (Box 36)
  - Inauguration - Humphrey Tonkin - Invitation, 1989 (Box 36)
  - Inauguration - Humphrey Tonkin - Committee, 1989 (Box 36)
  - Inauguration - Humphrey Tonkin - Documentation, 1989 (Box 36)
  - Inauguration - Brown University, 1989 (Box 36)
  - Institute on Aging (Box 36, Box 37)
  - Institute for Retirement Security - Aging Symposium, 2005-2006 (Box 37)
  - International Education - General, 1992-2005 (Box 37)
  - International Education - Asia (Box 37)
  - International Education - Joint Program - Italian (Box 37)
  - International Education - Joint Program - Paris, France (Box 37)
  - International Education - Joint Program - Paris, France - Correspondence (Box 37)
  - International Education - Joint Program - Lyons, France (Box 37)
  - International Education - Joint Program - Hertford, UK (Box 38)
  - International Education - Joint Program - Hertford, UK - Martin Trust (Box 38)
  - International Education - University of Warsaw Bialystok - Funding (Box 37)
  - International Education - University of Warsaw Bialystok (Box 37)
  - International Education - Poland - Funding 1 (Box 39)
  - International Education - Poland - Bialystok Polytechnic (Box 39)
  - International Education - Poland - Jagiellonian University (Box 39, Box 40)
  - International Education - Poland - Jagiellonian University Funding, 1990 (Box 40)
  - Lamplighters - Short Lessons, 2004 (Box 40)
  - Lamplighters - Correspondence, 2003 - 2004 (Box 40)
  - Lecture Series - Ellsworth Lectures, 1987-1999 (Box 40, Box 41)
  - Lecture Series - Ellsworth Brochures, 1980-2006 (Box 41)
  - Lecture Series - George Burns (Box 41)
  - Lecture Series - Nicholas Negroponte, Being Digital, 1995-1996 (Box 41)
  - Lecture Series - International Themed Lectures (Box 41)
  - Lecture Series - Rogow Lectures, 1990-1997 (Box 41)
  - Lecture Series - Hertford Lecture, 2000-2002 (Box 41, Box 42)
  - Metro Hartford Alliance, 2002-2007 (Box 42)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) (Box 43)
  - New England Association of Schools and Colleges (NEASC) Reports, 1981-2001 (Box 43, Box 44)
  - New England Association of Schools and Colleges (NEASC), 1983-1992 (Box 44, Box 45)
  - New England Association of Schools and Colleges (NEASC) - American University (Box 46)
  - New England Association of Schools and Colleges (NEASC) - Clark University (Box 46)
  - New England Association of Schools and Colleges (NEASC) - Suffolk University (Box 46, Box 47)
  - New England Council (Box 48)
  - Regents - Finance Committee Meetings, 2005 Nov 4 - 2008 April 25 (Box 48, Box 49)
  - Regents - Full Board Meeting, 2007 Feb 15 - Nov 30, undated (Box 49, Box 50)
  - Regents - Investment Subcommittee, 2007 Jun 14 - Sep 21 (Box 50)
  - Regents - Physical Plant Committee, 2007 Aug 2 (Box 50)
  - Regents - Walter Harrison Correspondence - Virginia Tech (Box 50)
  - Regents - Ralph Hart (Box 50)
  - Regents - Susan and Kent McCray (Box 50)
  - Regents - Louis Sampliner (Box 50)
  - Regents - George Weis - Say Yes to Education (Acc. 2011.18) (Box 51)
  - Regents - Letters to Regents from Walter Harrison, collected by Charles Condon, 1999 - 2005 (Box 51)
  - Regents - Ennisknupp financial reports and reviews, 2006-2007 (Box 51, Box 52)
  - Regents - Guggenheim - Real Estate, 2007 (Box 52)
  - Saint Francis Board of Directors, 2006-2007 (Box 52, Box 53)
  - Strategic Planning - Barney School of Business, Circa 1980 - circa 2000 (Box 53)
  - Strategic Planning - College of Arts and Sciences, 1987 (Box 53)
  - Strategic Planning - College of Basic Studies, 1987 (Box 53)
  - Strategic Planning - ENHP, 1987 (Box 53)
  - Strategic Planning - College of Engineering 1990-1995 (Box 53)
  - Strategic Planning - SPC - Collegiate Reorganization CETA/SETIC, 2001 (Box 53)
  - Strategic Planning - Hartford Art School, 1987, 1989 (Box 53)
  - Strategic Planning - Hartt School, 1988-1989 (Box 53)
  - Strategic Planning - University Functions (Box 53)
  - Strategic Planning - Ward, 1989 (Box 53)
  - Strategic Planning - University - SPAT and SPC, 1989-2008 (Box 53, Box 54, Box 55, Box 56, Box 57, Box 58, Box 59, Box 60, Box 61)
    Scope and Contents
    This file consists of notes, memorandums, correspondence, and reports of the Strategic Planning Committee (SPC) and the Strategic Planning Advisory Team (SPAT), as well as their respective sub-committees.
    Arrangement
    This file is arranged in rough chronological order.
  - Strategic Planning - UHart - HCW Affiliation, 1987-1996 (Box 61, Box 62)
  - Strategic Planning - HCW - SPC Phase I, 2003-2004 (Box 62, Box 63)
  - Strategic Planning - HCW - SPC Phase II, 2004 (Box 63)
  - Strategic Planning - HCW - SPC, 2002-2006, undated (Box 63, Box 64, Box 65)
  - Strategic Planning - WELFund, 2006 (Box 65)
  - Suffield Academy Board of Trustees (Box 65, Box 66)
  - Trachtenberg (Box 66)
    Contains information regarding: the Cosmos Club, Francine Z Trachtenberg, George Washington University (including inauguration and correspondence with Walter Harrison), Hebrew University, intercollegiate correspondence, media coverage, photos, speeches, Trachtenberg Fund, and University of Hartford HJG Center groundbreaking remarks.
  - University Magnet School (Box 66, Box 67)
    This file contains: design plans, groundbreaking photos, the school's first yearbook, curriculum, as well as memorandums and studies regarding the creation and operation of the school.
  - University High School (Box 68)
    This file documents the creation of the University High School including the proposal to the Woodrow Wilson National Fellowship Foundation and the Memorandum of Agreement.
  - University of Hartford - Aetna-Weaver-Ward Program (Box 68)
  - University of Hartford - Fall Kick Off, 2002-2008 (Box 68)
  - University of Hartford - Recognition Day (Box 69)
  - University of Hartford - Public Safety Unionization - RESTRICTED, 1987-1989 (Box 69)
  - University of Hartford - Public Safety, Strike Plan [RESTRICTED] (Box 69)
  - University of Hartford - Public Safety (Box 69)
  - University of Hartford - HRD - Affirmative Action (Box 69)
  - University of Hartford - 50th Anniversary (Box 69)
  - University of Hartford - Development Experiments - Griffin Center (Box 69)
  - University of Hartford - Development Experiments - Griffin Line (Box 69)
  - University of Hartford - Development Experiments - University Park (Box 70)
  - University of Hartford - Development Experiments - UofH and Watkinson School (Box 70)
  - University of Hartford - Development Experiments - World Skate (Box 70)
  - University of Hartford - Handel Center Opening (Box 70)
  - University of Hartford Campus Growth Development - Computer Center (Box 71)
  - University of Hartford Campus Growth Development - Handel Performing Arts Center (Box 71)
  - University of Hartford Campus Growth Development - ISET (Box 71, Box 77)
  - University of Hartford Campus Growth Development - University of Albany (Box 71)
  - University of Hartford Campus Growth Development - Village Apartments (Box 71)
  - University of Hartford Students - Hartford Half Tuition (Hartford Scholars) [PARTIALLY RESTRICTED] (Box 72)
    Conditions Governing Access
    The sixth folder of this file is restricted. Only accessible to President's Office staff.
  - University of Hartford Students - Hillel (Box 72)
    Documents the President's Office interactions with the student organization, including Hillel's roast of University President Walter Harrison.
  - University of Hartford Students - Measles, 1989-1994 (Box 73)
  - University of Hartford Students - Race Relations, 1995 Oct. 16 Incident [RESTRICTED], 1995-1996 (Box 73)
    This file is restricted. Access is available to President's Office Staff.
  - University of Hartford Students - Student Affairs (Box 73)
  - University of Hartford Students - Student Death Policy (Box 73)
  - University of Hartford Students - Substance Abuse (Box 73, Box 74)
  - University of Hartford - Institutional Research (Box 74, Box 77)
  - University of Hartford Committee - Collegiate Structure, 1993-1994 (Box 74)
  - University of Hartford Committee - Degree Ceremonies, 2008-2009 (Box 74)
  - University of Hartford Accreditation, 1996-2001, undated (Box 74)
  - University of Hartford Compensation Committee [RESTRICTED], 1995-2001 (Box 74, Box 75)
    This file is restricted. It is available only to the President's Office staff.
  - Calendars (Box 75)
  - Miscellaneous (A, B, and C) (Box 75)
  - Museum of American Political Life (Box 75, Box 76)
  - Lecture - New Directions in Economic Policy, 1982 (Box 76)
  - Lecture - Newman Lecture, 2008 (Box 76)
- Acc. II Unknown
- Acc. 2014.9
- Acc. 2016-03-11-01/2016-09-02-01, 1974-2012; Bulk 1987-2009; Accession 2016-03-11-01 and 2016-09-02-01; 3.35 Linear Feet (10 containers)
  - Brochures and Pamphlets, 2008, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Development - Alumni, 1998-2005 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Development - Major Prospects, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Donor Relations, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - External Funding, 2005-2008 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - F Miscellaneous, 1985; 2000-2007, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Facilities, 2005-2009 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - G Miscellaneous, 2003-2012, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Gordon, Richard Associates, 1989-1992 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Governor, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Graduate Studies, 1994-2009, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Harry Jack Gray, 2005; 2008, undated (Box 2, Folder 2-4)
  - Harry Jack Gray Conference Center, 1989-2005, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Gray Humanities Chair, 2005-2006 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Greenberg Center, 2002-2009 (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
  - GSU (Gengras Student Union), 1995-2002, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - High School of Science and Engineering, University, 2004 Dec 8 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Higher Ed., 2009 Jun (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Holiday Cards, 2005-2009 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Holiday Letters, 1974-2009 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Holiday Parties, 2003-2011 (Box 3, Folder 1-12)
  - Homecoming, 2001-2008 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Honorary Degrees, 2003-2007 (Box 3, Folder 14-16)
  - Housing, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Housing, International, 1991; 1993 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Israeli Bonds, 1987-2002 (Box 3, Folder 19, Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Ketchum, 1997 Apr (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Kosher Meal Plan, 2000 Nov - 2001 Jun (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Labau - Architects, 1991-1992; 2005, undated (Box 4, Folder 4, Box Shared Oversized 1)
  - Landscape Master Plan, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 5-6, Box 9)
  - Learning Disabilities, 1991-1999 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Lee, Percy, 1990-2002 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Legislators, 1998-2008 (Box 4, Folder 9-10)
  - Magnet School [PARTIALLY RESTRICTED], 2006-2009, undated (Box 4, Folder 11, Box 5, Folder 1-2)
  - Minority Affairs Committee, 1995-2006 (Box 5, Folder 3-5)
  - Moshe Katsav, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 6-8)
  - Nellie Mae Foundation, 1991-2004 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - New England Banking Institute, 1992-1997 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - North Hartford Initiative, 1998, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Office of Communication, 2006; 2008 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Olzacki, Joe, 2001-2006, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Optimal Sizing, 2004-2006 (Box 6, Folder 3-5)
  - Organizational Charts, 1991-2012 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - P-20 Commission, 2009-2011 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Phi Beta Kappa, 1987-2002 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Photographs, 1989; 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Presidential Communications Task Group, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Project Kaleidoscope, 2004-2006 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Psychology, A&S [Arts and Sciences], 1998-2004 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Puerto Rico, 1995-2001 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Recognition Day, 2010-2012 (Box 6, Folder 14-16)
  - Rental Space Task Force, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Residential Colleges, 1990-2007 (Box 7, Folder 2-3)
  - Retention, 1994-2000 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Rising Star Breakfast, MetroHartford Alliance, 2007 Feb 13 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - ROTC, 2008 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - S.I.F.E. Lines, 1990 - circa 2006 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - South Cottage, 1992 Dec - 1993 May; 1997 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Student Affairs [PARTIALLY RESTRICTED], 2000 - 2008 (Box 7, Folder 9-12)
    Privileged attorney work product material is restricted to President's Office and Legal Counsel staff only.
  - Student Government Association (SGA), 1990 - 2008 (Box 7, Folder 13-14)
  - SYTE Public Schools [PARTIALLY RESTRICTED], 1990 - 2003 (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
    One folder of the file is restricted to President's Office staff only until 2094. FERPA restricted.
  - Technology, 1997 - 2001 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Thomas, Nancy, 1998 - 2001 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Vinny Baker, 2003 Aug 10 (Box 8, Folder 6)